# Kira Pitman

# Web Developer

NZ Citizen 021 105 5248 kirapitman@gmail.com github.com/kira-pitman linkedin.com/in/kira-pitman

#### **About Me**

I am a full-stack software developer who recently completed Dev Academy Aotearoa living in Pōneke | Wellington. I bring with me 8 years of problem solving skills honed during both my study and professional contributions in experimental physics. Through my career pivot into tech, I have found that what sets me apart is my approach to challenges through analytical thinking and team planning. I thrive in environments that are inclusive, supportive, and allow for constructive collaboration. I hope my new career allows me to continue learning, and to contribute to meaningful and accessible technologies.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**Dev Academy Aotearoa** - Student - Full-Stack Development

June 2023 - October 2023

- A 15-week full immersion software development bootcamp at a total of 800 hours, working on multiple projects in a team environment with daily challenges and weekly 24 hour group projects
- Learned a modern web dev stack including **HTML5**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, **React**, **Knex**, **SQLite3**, **Node.js**, and **Express.js**, while having a strong emphasis on human skills as well as teamwork using agile methodologies.
- My team's final project, Tiff's Donuts, involved learning React Three Fiber to render and animate 3D donuts, not taught within the scope of the bootcamp. I was the agile facilitator for the project and facilitated stand up, managed sprints, and prioritized tasks to successfully deploy our project ahead of schedule.

**Lab Demonstrator** - Victoria University of Wellington

March 2023 - June 2023

- Primary lab demonstrator for 100-level engineering and physics course at VUW
- Collaborated with academics coordinating the lab course to deliver laboratory sessions for 40 students and independently marked lab reports and weekly assignments.
- Lead full classes and worked one-on-one with students as requested to support their learning.

**Junior Scientist** - OpenStar Technologies

July 2022 - January 2023

• Simulation and early development of flux pump power systems to be used in conjunction with a permanent levitated dipole fusion system.

- Primary focus on the assembly, testing, iteration, and analysis of this high-temperature superconducting technology.
- Developed my technical skills of computational simulation of power systems in Matlab, control systems engineering, and the facilitation of design processes.

#### Lab Technician - Paihau | Robinson Research Institute

Dec 2020 - March 2022

- Lab technician in the head-MRI project at Paihau | Robinson Research Institute, primarily on production of the 2nd generation HTS coils used for the MRI machine.
- Worked in a small team of engineers and technicians to meet fast deadlines and work at a high level under pressure.
- Exhibited strong attention to detail during the preparation, handling, and organization of 15km of fragile superconducting wire.
- Created and managed the coil winding schedule which allocated roles for before, during, and after winding to streamline the production process, and directed the winding process on production days.

#### Research Assistant - Paihau | Robinson Research Institute

August 2020 - December 2020

- Set up a laser pressure measurement system and sputtering system for research at a microscopic level.
- Formulated experimental procedures with necessary health and safety requirements.

#### **High School Tutor** - *Inspiration Education*

July 2015 - December 2020

- Communicated scientific information for physics, chemistry, and mathematics in a non-academic format to a range of recipients.
- Collaborated with students to identify areas of growth, and strategically plan to meet their long-term intrinsically motivated goals.
- Planned lessons for allotted time to build skills and rapport to allow for both academic and personal growth in students.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Web Development Training Scheme, Level 6 Certificate - Dev Academy Aotearoa

June 2023 - October 2023

Master of Science - Victoria University of Wellington

March 2019 - May 2020

## Bachelor of Science (First Class Hons.) - Victoria University of Wellington

March 2015 - December 2018

## **References** Available on request